Guide to the Richard Pollay Acme Advertising Collection, 1850s-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Series 12: Catalogs, 1890-2004 and undated
  - 100-12-046. Acme Card System Company. Catalog, 1930 (Box 37)
    Profitable Business Control with Acme Visible Records. Cover creased lower left corner. Good condition.
  - 100-12-047. Central Intelligence Agency (CIA). Booklet, 1979 (Box 37)
    The Acme of Skill. Information on CIA and function. Spine shows tears. Staining from coffee (?) cup on cover. Good condition.
  - 100-12-048. National Acme Company (NAMCO). Catalog, 1922 (Box 37)
    String binding. Raised green lettering on cover, some staining evident. Good condition.
  - 100-12-049. Acme Tackle Company. Catalog, undated (Box 37)
    America's finest line of nationally advertised metal lures... Color images of fishing tackle. Good condition.
  - 100-12-050. Acme Juicer Manufacturing Company. Brochure, undated (Box 37)
    Acme Juicer. The Fountain of Life. Color photographs. Good condition.
  - 100-12-051. Acme Juicer Manufacturing Company. Brochure, undated (Box 37)
    Acme Juicer. The Fountain of Life. Color images and photographs. Red paper stuck to back. Good condition.
  - 100-12-052. Acme Head and Body. Brochure, undated (Box 37)
    Hair care services and prices, schedule, location information. Some stains. Good condition.
  - 100-12-053. Acme Barbeque College. Manual, 1955 (Box 37)
    Official text Book Acme BBQ College. Pen markings. Cover creased and some staining. Hole punched. Fair condition.
  - 100-12-054. Acme Chain Corporation. Catalog, undated (Box 37)
    Roller chains and sprockets images, specifications and other information. Hole punched and stapled binding. Good condition.
  - 100-12-055. Acme Chair Company. Acme Folding Chairs catalog No. 40, 1920s (Box 37)
    Embossed writing and decoration on cover. Product images and drawings throughout. Good condition.
  - 100-12-056. Acme Air Appliance Company. Catalog, 1968 (Box 37)
    Acme for Accuracy since 1915. Tire Hardware and Service Products. Item multiple hole-punched. Stains on cover. Good condition.
  - 100-12-057. Acme Fan Clutches. Catalog, undated (Box 37)
    No images, dealer information, dealer price list. Pages are torn and have rust marks from paper clip. Hole punched. Poor condition.
  - 100-12-058. Acme Washing Machine Company. Catalog, 1906 (Box 37)
    Washday comfort. Acme Washing Machines Wringer Mops Clothes Wringers. Cover detached. Some staining and discoloration. Black-and-white Images and text are clear. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-059. Underwriters Laboratories. Acme Stove brochure, undated (Box 37)
    For modern econ, thermostatic, slow-burn heat. Color pages and photos. Only part of the original.
  - 100-12-060. Acme Aircraft Corp. Brochure, undated (Box 37)
    Presenting the Acme Monoplane Sports Type Two-Seater of Latest Design. New and Safe. Image of plane and specifications. Folded three times. Good condition.
  - 100-12-061. Acme Boot Company. Catalog, 1969 (Box 37)
    A catalog of new dimensions. Black-and-white photographs with boot specifications. Good condition. A Subsidiary of Northwest Industries Inc.
  - 100-12-062. Acme Card System Company. Catalog, 1925 (Box 37)
    Acme Visible Records Equipment. Engraved images of people working with system advertised. Number 04 erased from front cover.
  - 100-12-063. Burr Manufacturing Company. Brochure, undated (Box 37)
    Burr Automatic Retoother For All Hand Saws. Provides specs and testimonials. Acme is the product line of saws available. Good condition.
  - 100-12-064. Acme Design Corp. Advertisement, 2003 (Box 37)
    Color photos of different beads. Contact information. Good condition.
  - 100-12-065. National Acme Company. Annual Report 1948, 1948 (Box 38)
    Directors, Officers, Registrars, Transfer Agents, financial information. Good condition.
  - 100-12-066. Acme Tractor Parts Company. Catalog, 1967 (Box 38)
    Tractor Parts Red Book Cat. Water damage evident. Tears and rust from stapled binding. Newsprint quality paper. Poor condition.
  - 100-12-067. Acme White Lead and Color Works. Catalog, 1939 (Box 38)
    Color Beautifies the Home. This book will show you the modern color trends and will help you in your selections. Images and text are in color. Good condition.
  - 100-12-068. Acme Road Machinery Company. Catalog No. 11, undated (Box 38)
    Decorative style indicates from the 1900-1920s? Catalog is in Spanish. Provides clear images of products, descriptions and specifications. Good condition.
  - 100-12-069. National Acme Company. Instruction Booklet for Operators of Model A Acme Automatics, undated (Box 38)
    Instruction booklet for Acme Automatic Multiple Spindle Screw Machine, Book stained throughout--oil? Rust on stapled binding. Text and images are clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-070. Acme Apparatus Bulletin T, 1925 (Box 38)
    Acme for Transmission. Images, specifications, operating directions and prices for transformers. Cover oil stained. Text and images clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-071. J. W. Pepper and Son. Acme Orchestra Collection by Mackie-Beyer, 1910? (Box 38)
    Instrumentation for first violin. Small tears on cover. Oil/grease stain. Good condition.
  - 100-12-072. Acme Tractor Supply Company. 1952 Cat, 1952 (Box 38)
    Nebraska's largest tractor supply house. Newsprint. Yellowing. Text and images clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-073. Donovan Farmers Co-operative Elevator Inc. Acme Farm Tips Newsletter, 1952 (Box 38)
    Monthly newsletter. Volume III, Number 6. Black-and-white photographs. Good condition.
  - 100-12-074. Acme White Lead and Color Works. Painting guide book, 1928 (Box 38)
    The sign of paint success--Complete information and detailed methods of preparing surfaces and applying Acme quality paints, enamels, lacquers, stains and varnishes. Good condition.
  - 100-12-075. Acme Woven Wood Lath Company. Booklet, 1908 (Box 38)
    An Illustrated Exhibit. at Dallas Texas Sate Fair, 1908. Black-and-white images and text. Folded. Some small tears. Good condition.
  - 100-12-076. Unknown. Acme Typewriter Tablet, undated (Box 38)
    Tablet for preventing waste. Fine white paper especially made for typewriter use and correspondence. 2 sheets of paper attached. Some fading on cover. Good condition.
  - 100-12-077. Acme Fireless Cooker Company. Catalog, 1913 (Box 38)
    Advance announcement of the new 1913 line...Many new and important features. Testimonials and features. Catalog folds out. Pencil markings on cover. Small tears, staining. Good condition.
  - 100-12-078. Acme Newark Machine Works Inc. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Music roll Machinery. Music Roll Perforator advertised. Black-and-white images and text. Good condition.
  - 100-12-079. Acme Manufacturing Company. Folding Boats Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    A marvel of portability and comfort. Black-and-white photographs. Text clear. Small folding tears. Good condition.
  - 100-12-080. Acme Bulletin and Directory board Corp. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    A complete service of changeable signs. Changeable letters. Changeable strips. Torn along spine and stapled. Images and text clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-081. Acme Sparkler and Specialty Company. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Color, sketched images. Product information and prices. Good condition.
  - 100-12-082. Acme Telectronix. Telephotograph catalog, 1951 (Box 38)
    Acme telephotograph transmitters, specifications and product models. Images and text clear. Item folded. Good condition.
  - 100-12-083. Acme Lite Manufacturing Company. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    A brief guide to better lighting. Images and text clear. Folded. Good condition.
  - 100-12-084. Acme White Lead and Color Works. Painting stencil set, undated (Box 38)
    Free Complete Decorating Outfit. King Color Rules the Home. Color images on cover. Directions. Some tearing. Paper creased and worn in places. Text clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-085. Acme Safe. Brochure, undated (Box 38)
    The Alphabet Line Fire Proof Safes. Built for strength and heat resistance. Folding has cut the edges. Images and text clear. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-086. Acme Wagon Company. Brochure, undated (Box 38)
    All Acme Wheels Dipped in Boiling Oil. Exclusive features and improvements. Folded. Some stains. Text and images clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-087. Acme Coppersmithing and Machine Company. Booklet, undated (Box 38)
    Process Plant Equipment. Black-and-white photographs. Text and images clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-088. Acme Body Top Company. Car specifications, 1927? (Box 38)
    Pamphlet advertises various body types for certain vehicles. Black and white print and images with blue color added to car images. Document is punch-holed and two sided. Good condition.
  - 100-12-089. Acme Trans-Pacific Mail Order Service. Brochure, undated (Box 38)
    Beige paper, brown printing, sketches and photographs used. Item folds quite small. Pencil notes on cover. Fragile.
  - 100-12-090. Duane H. Nash. Brochure, 1919? (Box 38)
    Acme Pulverizing Harrow. The Coulters Do the Work. Aimed at dealers. Black-and-white. Some yellowing. Folded. Pencil markings on back. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-091. Acme Merit-thon. Flyer, 1979 (Box 38)
    People running for people. Run For The Jimmy Fund. Good condition.
  - 100-12-092. Acme Janitor Service. Brochure, undated (Box 38)
    Advertises janitorial services and contact information. Good condition.
  - 100-12-093. Cuckovich Bros. Acme Grill. Menu, 1941 (Box 38)
    Oakland's Oldest and Most Modern Restaurant. Pricing and food/beverages. Brown card. Some stains. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-094. Unknown. Acme Nicotine Delouser, undated (Box 38)
    Paint the Perches. Controls Chicken Lice. No Lice- More Eggs. Stained and tears. Merchant stamp on front: L. H. Nester, PA Poor condition.
  - 100-12-095. Acme Brick Company. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Complete line of bricks described. Photographs of buildings built with Acme Brick. Black-and-white images and text. Good condition.
  - 100-12-096. Duane H. Nash Inc. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Acme Pulverizing Harrow, Clod Crusher, and Leveler. Red and yellow decorative design cover. Black-and-white images and text are clear. Minor markings. Good condition.
  - 100-12-097. Canadian Closet Shops. Acme Sliding Mirror Door, 1980? (Box 38)
    Acme Sliding Mirror Doors are a product line of Canadian Closet Shops.
  - 100-12-098. Acme White Lead and Color Works. Brochure, 1930s (Box 38)
    Acme Quality No-Luster Finish. 10 paint samples included. Color images. Tearing along folds. One section is detached from the rest of the document. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-099. Unknown. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Make your radiators harmonize with your interior. Tinted images. Clear text and images. Good condition.
  - 100-12-100. Acme Can Company. Freezer brochure, undated (Box 38)
    Recipes for Acme 5 Minute Freezer. Home made ice cream... Ca. 1920s? Blue images and text. Minor markings. Good condition. See: 100-01-31--wooden ice cream spike from same Company.
  - 100-12-101. Ritter Manufacturing Company. Acme Freezer brochure, undated (Box 38)
    A light kitchen utensil, rapid, econ, simple, sanitary. 2 quart size $1.00 Color images. Ca. 1920s? Steinfeild Bros. Distrib. Tears along folds. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-102. Acme Tackle Company. Catalog, 1958 (Box 12)
    Acme Tackle Company. Presents Lightning Lures for 1958. Black-and-white images and text. Pages missing? Punch holed. Good condition.
  - 100-12-103. Acme Electric and Manufacturing Company. Catalog, 1941? (Box 12)
    Small blue catalog of full product line for dealers. Good condition.
  - 100-12-104. Acme Watches. Display folder, undated (Box 12)
    The double Feature Line. Quality and Style at Popular Prices. Vinyl Embossed cover. Black velvet inside cover. Good condition.
  - 100-12-105. Red Kap Industries. Catalog, undated (Box 12)
    Red Kap comfortable clothes for work. Distributed by Acme Uniforms for Industry. Circa 1990-2000? Email address for contact available. Good condition.
  - 100-12-106. Unknown. Clothing catalog, 2002 (Box 12)
    Company is not identified. Distributed by Acme Uniforms for Industry. Email address for contact available. Good condition.
  - 100-12-107. Acme Distributors Ltd. Catalog, undated (Box 12)
    Modern Equipment for Better Farming. Good condition.
  - 100-12-108. Acme Key Company. Catalog 52, undated (Box 12)
    Catalog of keys. Red staining inside pages. Good condition.
  - 100-12-109. Acme Chain Corp. Roller Chains and Sprockets Catalog, 1963? (Box 12)
    Product catalog. Red pen on cover, Dave 11/6/63 catalog no. 14. Good condition.
  - 100-12-110. Acme Jewelers Supply Company. Catalog, 1952 (Box 12)
    Quick fit. Showing complete interchangeability. --Swiss Material Systems. Cover taped w/black tape. Dealers catalog faded and stained. Some tearing. Text and images are clear. Poor condition.
  - 100-12-111. Acme Lanterns Inc. Catalog, 1954 (Box 12)
    Distinctive Lighting. Original Designs. Text and images clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-112. Acme School Supply Company. Catalog, undated (Box 12)
    Complete School Service. Includes insurance and postage rates. Text and images clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-113. Acme Novelty Ltd. Catalog, 1968 (Box 12)
    Our 36th Year. Color images. Distributor's catalog. Text clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-114. Acme Machinery Company. Catalog, 1916 (Box 12)
    Bolt Nut and Forging Machines. Text and images are clear. Cover stamped w/illegible name. Stained. Cover separated from body. Water damage. Paper disintegrating. Fragile. Poor condition.
  - 100-12-115. Acme Backing Corp. Planner, 1945 (Box 12)
    Louis Charleroy embossed in small gold letters on cover. Binding is starting to separate from pages. Pages are yellowing with some staining. Good condition.
  - 100-12-116. Acme Poultry Company. Planner, 1962 (Box 12)
    Vinyl cover. Address section. Small writing pad. Pen scribbled under cover page. Good condition.
  - 100-12-117. I. F. Segner and Company. Acme file, 1907? (Box 12)
    Just the thing for Safety deposits. Directions for use and price $1.25. Envelopes have entries--names and type of document. Ribbon (?) binding. Fragile. Good condition.
  - 100-12-118. Acme Radio Supply Inc. Catalog, 1955 (Box 12)
    Radio, Sound, Amateur Supplies. Text and images are clear. Cover has small tears. Good condition.
  - 100-12-119. Acme Brick Company. Monthly planner, 2004 (Box 12)
    Planner is unused. Includes testimonial from value customer. Contact information. A Berkshire Hathaway Company. Good condition.
  - 100-12-120. Acme Printing and Stationery Company. Binder, 1924? (Box 12)
    Leather cover, metal spine. 3 hole punch. Inside cover: National ROYAL No. 4760 in gold lettering. Some dividers and lined pages. Some pen text on one insert. Good condition.
  - 100-12-121. Acme Fishing Tool Company. Catalog, 1938 (Box 12)
    Cat. No. 12--The Mark of Highest Quality Since 1900. Water damage. Staining. Binding separating from body. Text and images clear. Fair condition.
  - 100-12-122. Acme Stationery and Paper Company. Drawing tablet, 1886? (Box 12)
    Engraved imagery on cover. Cover detached. Pages separated by tracing paper. Pencil sketches on pages. Most are dated. One signed: K. L. Norris. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-123. Acme Specialties. Fireworks catalog, 1987 (Box 38)
    1987 colored catalog and price list of fireworks from Acme Specialties Dist. Company, supplier and manufacturer of fireworks since 1918. Largest importer of Class C fireworks in the United States.
  - 100-12-124. Cleveland Pump And Foundry Company. Acme Oil Pump brochure, undated (Box 38)
    Larger profits, More sales, Less expense, Through the use of the Acme Oil Pump. Blue sketched images. Some staining. Good condition.
  - 100-12-125. Acme Boat Company. Brochure, 1929 (Box 38)
    Acme Outboards for 1929. Text and images clear. Excellent condition.
  - 100-12-126. I. F. Segner and Company. Acme file, 1907? (Box 12)
    Just the thing for Safety deposits. Directions for use and price $1.25. Some envelopes have entries--names and type of document. Dates range from 1920-1930s. Red ribbon binding. Fragile. Good condition.
  - 100-12-127. Acme White Lead and Color Works. Brochure, undated (Box 38)
    Acme Quality Varno-lac. For Floors, Furniture, and Woodwork Stains and Varnishes at One Operator. Samples of stain colors. Color images. Some staining. Good condition.
  - 100-12-128. Duane H. Nash Inc. Directions for Setting Up Pulverizing Harrow, undated (Box 38)
    Duane H. Nash: Directions for Pulverizing Harrow, Clod Crusher, and Leveler No. 14. Folded. Yellowing. Paper stained, dirt. Images and text clear. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-129. Acme Creative Enterprises. Booklet, undated (Box 38)
    Alphabet Soup...A taste of grammar for the non-grammarian. Insert inscribed to Rick Pollay from John. Excellent condition.
  - 100-12-130. Acme MFG. Company. Boat catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Now build your own boat and save money...The Acme Sea Mate. Black-and-white photographs. Text and images clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-131. Acme Comedy Company. Theatre programme, undated (Box 38)
    Up coming Calendar. Actors biographies, with dates of appearance. Email contact information. Good condition.
  - 100-12-132. Acme Harvesting Machine Company. Brochure, undated (Box 38)
    as ye sow so shall ye reap. -- Acme Hercules Wide Track Seeder. Acme Surprise End Gate Seeder. Tearing on edges. Fading. Images and text clear. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-133. Lautz Bros. and Company. Premium catalog, 1895 (Box 38)
    One trial will convince you that Acme is the best soap made! Lists articles to acquire with soap wrappers. Images and text clear. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-134. Acme Cleansing Company. Brochure, undated (Box 38)
    Addressee: Stanley Garrity, 645 E 62, City. Acme Cleansing Company offers you freezing cold storage vaults at new low prices! Emphasis on storage of fur coats. Good condition.
  - 100-12-135. Page Woven Wire Fence Company. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Black-and-white catalog. Introduction, description, price list. Images and text clear. Good condition.
  - 100-12-136. Classen Bros. and Company. Acme Self Heating Iron instructions, 1892? (Box 38)
    If you have any trouble with the iron you may look for the cause in yourself and not in the iron. In pencil: Keep this book, and date. Images and text clear. Part in German. Some wearing of paper. Good condition.
  - 100-12-137. Acme Brokerage and Commission Company. Investment solicitation, undated (Box 38)
    Our Specialties: Grain and Provisions. Binding detached. Some rust. Text clear. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-138. Acme Pressed Steel Corp. Acme Rocket and Dixie flyers, 1949 (Box 32)
    Ever popular Rocket spreads fame throughout the land. Boys everywhere are asking by NAME for this outstanding Acme family member--Cross country distribution. 2 sided advertisement. Text and images clear. Excellent Condition. Taken from March Toy Fair Issue, 1949 Playthings Mag.
  - 100-12-139. Acme Automotive Finishes. Microfiche formula file, 1984 (Box 32)
    Red binder of microfiche--automotive finishes comprise the majority of fiche. File stained and grease marked/ Fair condition.
  - 100-12-140. Acme Truck Parts. Catalog, 1984 (Box 32)
    We build 'em like they used to. Color cover, black-and-white images and text. Good condition.
  - 100-12-141. Acme Steel Company of Canada Ltd. Catalog, 1977 (Box 32)
    Your single order source for quality products, fast delivery, local service. Black-and-white images and text. Excellent condition.
  - 100-12-142. Acme Steel Company. Catalog, 1958 (Box 38)
    Packaging and Loading Lumber For Shipment in Box Cars Instructions. Black images, yellow card. Good condition.
  - 100-12-143. Canadian Closet Shops. Catalog, 1985 (Box 38)
    The beautiful door and closet idea book. Color catalog. Some staining. Good condition.
  - 100-12-144. Acme Spring Inc. Catalog, undated (Box 38)
    Serving science and technology exclusively. Black-and-white photographs. Emphasis on quality of product, no specifications given. Loose inserts included. Good condition.
  - 100-12-145. Acme Merit-thon. Run for Jimmy Fund package, 1979 (Box 38)
    Blank sponsor form, small flyer, letter size flyer.
  - 100-12-146. Acme Merit-thon. Run for Jimmy Fund poster, 1979 (Box 38)
    Sign Up Here. Folded, some stains, good condition.
  - 100-12-147. Acme Books. Catalog 92-100, undated (Box 38)
    Specialists in literature of journalism/mass communication, has thousands of scarce and out-of-print books. Typed pages, no images. Business card attached. Good condition.
  - 100-12-148. Acme Construction Supply Company. Acme Tabloid Times, 1997 (Box 38)
    Special edition! Acme employees give the gift of Christmas. Newsprint. Black-and-white photographs. Good condition.
  - 100-12-149. Acme Ruler Company, Ltd. Catalog, 1980 (Box 38)
    Educational Products. Color and black-and-white images. Punch holed. Good condition.
  - 100-12-150. Acme Metal Stove. Brochure, 1978 (Box 38)
    Brochure gives features, dimensions. Dealers outlets included. Good condition.
  - 100-12-151. A-1 Electric and Plumbing Supply Company. Catalog, 1980 (Box 38)
    Individual inserts advertising Acme Stove. Multi-colored type, some red pen used. Includes letter to Rick Pollay in response for product information. Punch holed. Signed Roy. Good condition.
  - 100-12-152. Acme Aluminum Products. Flyer, undated (Box 38)
    Aluminum Windows and Awning Manufacturers and Installers. Black-and-white images. Folded. Some markings. Good condition.
  - 100-12-153. Ace-Acme. Catalog, 1995 (Box 32)
    Color product catalog. Good condition.
  - 100-12-154. Acme Tackle Company. Catalog, 1998 (Box 41)
    Action makes the difference. Color photographs. Mint condition.
  - 100-12-155. Duane H. Nash. Acme: Tillage Line price list, 1919? (Box 41)
    Pulverizing harrows price list. Text and images clear. Item stained and torn. Fragile condition.
  - 100-12-156. Acme Oyster House. Menu, 1996? (Box 41)
    Brown menu, black text and images. Contact information. Awards 1990s. Detailed menu and prices. Folded. Good condition.
  - 100-12-157. Acme Oyster House. Menu, undated (Box 41)
    Light brown paper, black/gray text and images. Detailed menu and prices. Folded. Good condition.
  - 100-12-158. Acme Advertising. Brochure, undated (Box 41)
    It is funny the ideas that hit you when you're stuck on the Queensway. Black-and-white images and text. Folded. Good condition.
    Link to Acme Advertising site
  - 100-12-159. Grant Thornton Chartered Accountants. Catalyst. Fall Issue 1998, 1998 (Box 41)
    www.GrantThornton.ca--Thinking of selling your business when you retire? Image on cover is an Acme business For Sale By Owner. Mint condition.
  - 100-12-160. Marketing Magazine, 1994 (Box 32)
    Front page image shows robot with image of Acme Shovel on chest. Same image appears on p. 14. Folded. Good condition.
  - 100-12-161. Acme Animation Art Gallery. Flyer, 1993 (Box 41)
    Chuck Jones...live on Broadway. Folded. Good condition.
  - 100-12-162. Acmetrack Ltd. Stanley. Acme Closet Organizers brochure, undated (Box 41)
    Great closets the do-it-yourself guide to increased space and beautiful new doors. Folded. Color. Good condition.
  - 100-12-163. Acme Computers. Flyer, 1995 (Box 41)
    Value, Service and Quality You Can Trust. Fax. Print from unrelated item shows up on this paper. Print quality is poor. Text readable.
  - 100-12-164. Acme Plastics Inc. Flyer, 1992 (Box 41)
    Find the pot of gold at Acme...Super Selection at Factory Outlet Prices. Folded. Good condition.